<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>A Pelican Blog</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/Ikke%20kategoriseret.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2011-08-29T13:55:00Z</updated><entry><title>Python rounding to 05</title><link href="/python-rounding-to-05.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-08-29T13:55:00Z</updated><author><name>kristian</name></author><id>tag:,2011-08-29:python-rounding-to-05.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here in Switzerland they decided (for some reason, that can't be good)
not to pay the correct amount, but round it to the nearest 0/5 cent -
which is a pain when doing python stuff. Therefore i made a Decimal
rounding function for python, check it out:
`` from decimal import Decimal, ROUND_HALF_UP  def decimal_round(d, digits=0, to_five=True):     if to_five:         d = (d/Decimal(&amp;quot;5&amp;quot;))     d = d.quantize(Decimal(&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;) / (Decimal('10') ** digits), rounding=ROUND_HALF_UP)     if to_five:         d = d * Decimal(&amp;quot;5&amp;quot;)     return d``&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Plugins (management) with RabbitMQ</title><link href="/plugins-management-with-rabbitmq.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-08-05T15:11:00Z</updated><author><name>kristian</name></author><id>tag:,2011-08-05:plugins-management-with-rabbitmq.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today i spent quite some time investigating why i could make the plugin
&amp;quot;management&amp;quot; run with RabbitMQ. I was running ubuntu 10.04 (LTS) and did
sudo apt-get install rabbitmq-server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, it was a mystery how to enable the plugins. There were no
default plugin directory existing, but thats solved by adding it
yourself. You can find your rabbitmq directory with whereis, e.g.
&amp;quot;whereis rabbitmq&amp;quot;. Then you just create a folder called &amp;quot;plugins&amp;quot;
inside the folder called rabbitmq_version, in my case:
/usr/lib/rabbitmq/lib/rabbitmq_server-1.7.2/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the above case, i didnt get it working, as the management interface
isn't compatible with 1.7.2, which is bundled with the LTS. So now I'm
investigating the possibility to upgrade it via their custom apt-get
repository available from their website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the reason why im writing this, is that i spent a lot of time
not beeing able to enable the plugins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have to run a script inside the bin folder in /usr/lib/rabbitmq/ -
both for enabling and disabling plugins&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Next Danish election threatened by workers union</title><link href="/next-danish-election-threatened-by-workers-union.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-02-21T23:15:00Z</updated><author><name>kristian</name></author><id>tag:,2011-02-21:next-danish-election-threatened-by-workers-union.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In Denmark we will soon have the next 4th yearly election for our
parliament &amp;quot;folketinget&amp;quot;. However, it seems to be threatened by the
workers union PROSA, whose members are maintaining some of the most
important IT systems in Denmark (including the police systems and the
tax authorities). All these systems are maintained by CSC, who made a
lockout of some of the works unions members, which resulted in a strike
for even more members. If you ask me CSC reminds me of overpriced public
IT projects - it always ends this way. Furthermore, its really common
that every time they finish a project, that they charged many tax moneys
for, it seems to be lacking functionality. However, the public IT
administration seems to be married with them and continues to pick them
for every project. I think this is a great example of the public IT
administration failing once again - never pick the same supplier for all
the public service systems - you risk loosing them all simultaneously.
Read more at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.comon.dk/nyheder/prosa-truer-folketingsvalg-1.391053.html"&gt;comon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>